faststream.gov.uk 2019-03-26

# Privacy and cookies policy | Civil Service Fast Stream

This notice sets out how we will use your personal data, and your rights. It is made under Articles 13 and/or 14 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

**YOUR DATA**

The data

We will process your personal data solely to update you about civil service talent programmes. 

This will include the data you provided to us: name, mobile number, email address.  
In addition when you visit one of our websites we will collect your IP address, details of which version of web browser you used and information on how you use the site (cookies and page tagging techniques). For more information about our cookies, see below. 

**Purpose**

The purpose(s) for which we are processing your personal data is to tell you about our talent programmes. Your personal data will only be used by us for the purposes described.

**Legal basis of processing**

The legal basis for processing your personal data is:

\- Because you consent to us doing so. We will not contact you about our programmes without your permission. This will be gained by asking you to opt in by ticking the appropriate box. We will make this consent form clear on all our marketing where we ask to capture your personal details.

**Recipients**

As your personal data will be stored on our IT infrastructure it will also be shared with our data processors who provide email, and document management and storage services to us.

Data will also be shared by us with the supplier that provides the online recruitment registration and on-boarding solution.

**Retention**

Your personal data will be kept by us for a maximum of two years unless otherwise stated.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the right to request information about how your personal data are processed, and to request a copy of that personal data.

You have the right to request that any inaccuracies in your personal data are rectified without delay.

You have the right to request that any incomplete personal data are completed, including by means of a supplementary statement.

You have the right to request that your personal data are erased if there is no longer a justification for them to be processed.

You have the right in certain circumstances (for example, where accuracy is contested) to request that the processing of your personal data is restricted.

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data where it is processed for direct marketing purposes.

You have the right to withdraw consent to the processing of your personal data at any time by emailing us at fsetoutreach@cabinetoffice.gov.uk

**COMPLAINTS**

If you consider that your personal data has been misused or mishandled, you may make a complaint to the Information Commissioner, who is an independent regulator.  The Information Commissioner can be contacted at:

Information Commissioner's Office

Wycliffe House

Water Lane

Wilmslow

Cheshire

SK9 5AF

0303 123 1113

casework@ico.org.uk

Any complaint to the Information Commissioner is without prejudice to your right to seek redress through the courts.

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

As your personal data is stored on our IT infrastructure, and shared with our data processors who provide email, and document management and storage services to us, it may be transferred and stored securely outside the European Economic Area. Where that is the case it will be subject to equivalent legal protection through the use of Model Contract Clauses.

**CONTACT DETAILS**

The data controller for your personal data is the Cabinet Office. The contact details for the data controller are:

Cabinet Office

70 Whitehall

London

SW1A 2AS

0207 276 1234

publiccorrespondence@cabinetoffice.gov.uk

The contact details for the data controller’s Data Protection Officer (DPO) are:

Stephen Jones

DPO

Cabinet Office

70 Whitehall 

London

SW1A 2AS

**COOKIES POLICY**

This section describes our cookies policy for [www.faststream.gov.uk](http://www.faststream.gov.uk/).

www.faststream.gov.uk puts small files (known as ‘cookies’) onto your computer to collect information about how you browse the site.

Cookies are used to:

  * measure how you use the website so it can be updated and improved based on your needs
  * remember the notifications you’ve seen so that we don’t show them to you again

www.faststream.gov.uk cookies aren’t used to identify you personally. You’ll normally see a message on the site before we store a cookie on your computer. Find out more about [how to manage cookies](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

Measuring website usage (Google Analytics)

We use software to collect information about how you use [www.faststream.gov.uk](http://www.faststream.gov.uk/). stores information about:

  * how you got to the site
  * what you click on while you’re visiting the site
  * how long you spend on the site
  * how long you spend on each link page you click through to
  * what you click on once at the page you’ve clicked through to

We don’t collect or store your personal information (eg your name or address) so this information can’t be used to identify who you are. We don’t allow Google to use or share our analytics data. 

**Targeting**

Targeting cookies are linked to services provided by our trusted partners, as listed below.

You decide whether or not these cookies are used.

**We use targeting cookies to:**

  * Link to social networks who may use information about your visit to target advertising to you on other websites
  * Provide advertising agencies with information on your visit so that we can present adverts that you may be interested in
  * Deliver content, including video content, tailored to your interests 

Google Analytics sets the following cookies:

Universal Analytics

Name

| 

Purpose

| 

Expires  
  
---|---|---  
  
_ga

| 

This helps us count how many people visit www.faststream.gov.uk   
by tracking if you’ve visited before

| 

2 years  
  
_gat

| 

Used to manage the rate at which page view requests are made

| 

10 minutes  
  
Google Analytics

Name

| 

Purpose

| 

Expires  
  
---|---|---  
  
_utma

| 

Like _ga, this lets us know if you’ve visited before, so we can count how many of our visitors are new to www.faststream.gov.uk or to a certain page

| 

2 years  
  
_utmb

| 

This works with _utmc to calculate the average length of time you spend on www.faststream.gov.uk

| 

30 minutes  
  
_utmc

| 

This works with _utmb to calculate when you close your browser

| 

when you       close your               browser  
  
_utmz

| 

This tells us how you reached this website (eg from another website or a search engine)

| 

6 months  

**Our introductory message**

You may see a pop-up welcome message when you first visit www.faststream.gov.uk. We’ll store a cookie so that your computer knows you’ve seen it and knows not to show it again.

Name

| 

Purpose

| 

Expires  
  
---|---|---  
  
cookies_accepted

| 

Saves a message to let us know that you’ve seen our cookie message

| 

1 month  
  
**YouTube videos**

We use YouTube to provide videos on some pages of the site. YouTube sets cookies when you visit one of these pages.

Name

| 

Purpose

| 

Expires  
  
---|---|---  
  
_use_hitbox

| 

This is a randomly generated number that identifies your browser

| 

When you close your browser  
  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE

| 

Lets Youtube count the views of embedded Youtube videos

| 

9 months  
  
PREF

| 

Lets Youtube count the views of embedded Youtube videos

| 

9 months  
  
YSC

| 

Lets Youtube count the views of embedded Youtube videos

| 

When you close your browser
